the early Buttonwood days where the
people would meet under the tree to
trade shares of companies amongst
themselves. I believe that's how like
the New York Stock Exchange got started.
Right away I understood, okay, this is
the biggest thing. This is like the
biggest opportunity that I've ever heard
in my life.
And the debt burden, you know, whatever
you got right at $38 trillion, but at
some point bond market will break and
there'll be like a rush to Bitcoin.
How much time do we have? Say at least 5
years, maybe it'll be at 50,000, 1.2
million 10 years from now.
>> [music]
>> It is our very pleasure to have Austin
here with us. He is the partner of 10X
Capital. Hello. Hello, yeah.
Nice setup you got here. You guys are
doing great.
>> Thank you. I want to go back to 20,
sorry, 2013
when you started the first Bitcoin
physical Bitcoin exchange. Yeah, I
believe it was the first. Uh
That is huge. Uh well, could have been
bigger. It was cool. Right.
>> cool.
>> Okay. How did you come up with the
concept?
Well, I was like kind of buying and
selling Bitcoin already for some time
and I knew uh
there was like a a scene and I was
living in New York City and there was a
scene there developing of people who
were kind of doing local trades
together. Describe that to me
because it's so far away. Like
a small group of people, I assume.
>> Small, but you know, it grew very
quickly.
I wasn't even like even in there in the
first
in the beginning beginning.
Um
So, there was like a like a like a
Bitcoin meetup Mhm. that uh started um I
believe it's I believe it started right
at the end of 2012 and then uh picked up
pace in 2013 as you know, kind of the
whole industry did because in 2013, you
remember there was kind of two
separate
uh pumps, you know, there was like in
the beginning of the year
uh Bitcoin went to like almost $100, I
think.
>> Wow. And that was like a big deal, uh
you know, because
that was the first time that had
happened. I think in 2012, there was a
point in 2012 where
I think it was like less than $10 and
then
so for it to go, I think it was like
February or March of 2013, it hit like
$100. That was a really big deal. Um and
then they went back down to like sub 60,
sub 50 and then obviously as we all
remember, by the end of the year it had
hit a thousand and that was like a a
massive thing. So, in New York, they had
these meetups of
Bitcoin enthusiasts as they still do all
over the world. I'm sure they still do
them in New York.
Um and part of that was kind of a live
trading floor reminiscent of the uh the
early Buttonwood days where the people
would uh uh meet under the tree to trade
uh shares of companies amongst
themselves, which was kind of how the I
believe that's how like the New York
Stock Exchange got started.
>> Really? Yeah, they would meet under the
Buttonwood tree like near Wall Street.
Uh on Wall Street, there was a tree.
>> Yeah. And that tree was kind of the Huh.
>> location for for kind of the trading pit
where they were
I don't know. I'm probably butchering
this story, but it's something like
that. It was I remember it was the
Buttonwood tree.
And so we had a something where people
would
um
make the market in person. There was
like a cash market for Bitcoin in person
and people would come there and to buy
and sell Bitcoin uh in with cash
during the meetups and
um so, I didn't really know anything
about markets before that and then but
then being there for that and you know,
I started like trading Bitcoin myself
uh somewhat and then I
kind of realized that you know, probably
a Bitcoin exchange was a good business.
My first guy I didn't I didn't
understand how
I see.
>> I could see was like the best
opportunity I'd ever seen in my life.
That I understood, but I didn't know
how. So, I went and I bought some
Bitcoin from somebody.
Actually from Joseph Lubin.
Wow.
>> bought Bitcoin from Joseph Lubin.
>> did you do that? So, back in the days,
did you have to exchange you have to
meet him or Yeah, so I uh wanted to buy
some Bitcoin. I had already kind of got
into Bitcoin a few years earlier, but I
was I didn't get like
uh fully obsessed. I think I was missing
something. And so then I went to go buy
Bitcoin after whatever 12 months of like
not thinking about it. Uh I went to go
buy Bitcoin and back then you could go
on Local Bitcoin. It was was probably
the biggest
Bitcoin website. I mean, Mount Gox
probably had more volume circulating
through it, but
but I think for sure Local Bitcoin was
the most profitable Bitcoin business.
They took 1% of all the They make
basically had like an escrow platform
where they would take 1% of the trade.
And um
so, you would answer a a classified ad
essentially that said, you know, I'm
selling Bitcoin or whatever and you So,
I would I I messaged the guy. I said,
"Oh, I want to buy some Bitcoin." And he
uh said uh "Meet me at the coffee shop
on 14th Street or something." I think it
was. And so, I went to the coffee shop
and then I met the guy and I think this
was really early too, 2013.
And I said, "Oh, I need some Bitcoin.
I need $50 of Bitcoin."
>> [laughter]
>> And he said, "Oh, do you want $50 of
Bitcoin or do you want $50 and also a
little extra for the mining fee?" And
when I had
learned about Bitcoin before like in
2011,
I don't think there was mining fee. Like
you would just send a There was just
like the the miners would mine with no
fee. It was like, you know, there was
never a wait or any I don't know. And
then um
I didn't know what he meant. So, I said,
"Why why why would I need the mining
fee? How does it work?" I started asking
questions about that and it ended up
uh
I had one of the, you know, smartest
people in the whole world luckily that I
had never met up with, which was Joseph
Lubin. And I asked him you know, how
does it work with the mining? And he
explained to me uh it was like at least
an hour he took to explain to me in
detail how the mining worked. And when I
left the coffee shop, I was like, "Oh my
god, this is huge." Cuz I'd already been
into I'd already been into Bitcoin a
little bit. I was really into gold and I
was just like really not into central
banking. I had looked into other
projects and that had failed like
Liberty Reserve and other things which I
don't really remember. I never like
invested financially in them much, but I
was following them and then they would,
you know, they got shut down by the
government. That and there was a couple
others.
And then
uh
that finally that conversation with him,
I finally realized why Bitcoin couldn't
be shut down like those other ones. I
never gotten it fully. And when I
realized, okay, it's like uh you know,
it has the mining is like an it anchors
it to the to reality so that no one can
like just, you know, the network is real
because it's anchored into reality
through the mining. And once I realized
that, I thought, "Wow, this is so big."
Uh and I remember walking back to my to
my office. It was like, you know, I
wasn't the boss.
>> [laughter]
>> I was walking to the office and I was
like, "Wow, I have to figure out how to
tell my boss that I'm not going to do
with this anymore. I'm only going to do
Bitcoin." So, I started thinking, "Well,
then what does that mean I'm only going
to do Bitcoin?" Cuz I I could understand
right away I understood, okay, this is
the biggest thing. This is like the
biggest opportunity that I've ever heard
in my life.
>> of financial gain
>> Just Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah. Like just
this is like the scale of it became I I
thought before had years before I was
like, "Okay, this kind of be big." But I
I didn't quite get it. Yeah.
>> So, but but that moment I got it. And as
soon as I got it, I was like, "Wow, this
is so big. It's so big like I don't I
clearly don't understand anything about
this. Like it's so big." Uh and I need
to just like completely focus on this.
And you know, it's like a wasn't a long
walk. It was, you know, half hour walk
max. So, I'm walking back and I'm trying
to sort myself out because right away I
was like I was like, "This is like some
This is what I have to focus on fully."
This is I cannot waste my my energy on
anything else. This is the biggest thing
that uh I've ever seen. But I didn't
know the the dot I couldn't connect is I
was like, "Okay, but what is the How do
I make money on it?" And
uh I didn't realize, okay, this if it
this is the money, the way that you make
money on it is get as much of it as
possible. Like that was kind of I guess
you could kind of understand that. I was
like, "Okay, but how do I get as much of
it as possible? I need to make I need to
make, you know, fiat. I need to make the
slave money." And uh Wait, you realized
that back then? I realized it on the
walk. I was like, "This is so heavy.
This is going to be so big. There's
clearly so much upside." But I didn't
like, you know, it was like a frantic
thing going on in my head. It was like I
didn't I didn't grasp like, "Okay, what
what do I do?" Like it's like it's like
everything is so the the scale of it is
so huge that it's like, you know,
imagine you have a a swarm of locust
coming at you. What do you do? You have
to get a net to try to catch as many as
possible. It's like the the scale is so
mind-boggling.
Uh so, I was already like in my head I
was already like years ahead. I was
like, "Wow, this is going to be so huge,
but then what do I do?" And so
I had went and bought Bitcoin from this
guy. So, I was like, "Oh, you need to
like sell Bitcoin. That's how you make
money by selling the Bitcoin." Trying to
sell Bitcoin and like set up this
infrastructure and it was it was good.
Uh I mean, it was a good idea. Mhm. Um
but you know, I'd never run an exchange
before and none of my
I'd never even traded on an exchange
before. I never did anything like that.
And uh neither did any of the partners I
had in the business, but we did
uh we were setting it up pretty well. We
had basically the entire framework for
instance. This is, you know, before
Kraken ever launched and this is uh back
then it was like Mount Gox
and Bitstamp were the only exchange. And
then there was a bunch of all coin
exchanges like Poloniex and Mint Pal and
Cryptsy.
And uh Coinbase didn't have an exchange.
They had like a brokerage. So, it's like
of all those I just mentioned were were
all the main and there was one called
Camp BT. No one remembers that one, but
that was, you know, somewhat relevant in
America.
And so what? Does one of those exchanges
still exist or something? Two of them?
Do I guess Bitstamp kind of still exist,
so two of those the major exchanges So
it's clearly a volatile industry. First,
we opened the Bitcoin Center, which was
like the physical event space for
Bitcoin, and we had a physical exchange
going on. We had a trading floor every
week.
Um like a like a open outcry trading
floor, and we were incubating some
Bitcoin businesses, and we had
we had a mining company that that set up
there, and um
they ended up going under like almost
every other mining company, but for a
while they were they were producing some
Bitcoin, and we had like a big Dogecoin
party there in 2014, actually, which was
covered by the media a lot. We had a lot
of media coverage back then. We were on
if you search like Bitcoin Center New
York, you'll find like CNBC segments and
CNN segments and
tons of media like that.
>> Did you have to convince people because
that that was so early? Yeah. Well, how
did people describe Bitcoin? Is it the
same?
Um no, there's definitely a lot of
differences. And so we were
we were like literally
stopping people in the street talking
about Bitcoin like in front of our space
there.
We were distributing
actually David Bailey, the guy who runs
this conference, we were distributing
his first We were the biggest
distributors for his first magazine,
which was called Why Bitcoin, before he
had purchased Bitcoin magazine. We also
were distributing Bitcoin magazine and a
bunch of other stuff. It's very rare
today, at least for me, that I start a
conversation for like the bare bones of
It's been years since I've like really
done that, or at least at any scale.
Back back then, anyone you spoke to was
like you have to assume that they never
heard of it ever. And now it's like, you
know,
world leaders and business leaders and
like every day every single day,
literally, there's news that back then
would have been like the biggest news of
the month or of the year. And now it's
every day there's something that would
have been considered, you know, and then
and anytime there was news like that, it
would pump the price massive
percentages, you know, like, "Oh, they
said Bitcoin on some TV show, and
Bitcoin's up 10%." Well, because they
said it on some random TV show. Stuff
like that.
If you could go back to that time, that
period of time, and
what would you tell yourself, and would
you have believed this future self? I
believed, for sure. I was I was already
like thinking of crazy Well, luckily I
got like very early on introduced to
like brilliant people who ended up
becoming very very very successful. So
it's kind of interesting to to like
think about it, like the those
relationships. But I was luckily I was
like being
in New York
was lucky enough to be around like a lot
of very talented people who saw it very
early and were also very enthusiastic.
It's not like they saw it and they
wanted to like sit in their room and
just pontificate solo. It's like, you
know, people were very excited to talk
about Bitcoin with all the other people
who wanted to talk about the Bitcoin, so
that I mean, it literally came to
dominate my life for still
it's still [laughter] obviously very
relevant in my life. But back then
the obsession was was serious, you know,
it was like completely obsessed all day
every day for years, so let's say.
>> because you you think this is going to
be huge in terms of value?
Or is it because of the
I don't know, decentralization,
the concept
>> was definitely that initially. I mean,
look, like I thought it would be huge in
terms of value, but it was like I was
very excited by by
I mean, for sure, very excited primarily
by its ability to like disintermediate
central banking and free the markets,
and I've always thought that
um central banking and setting the
interest rates in a in a top-down, you
know, controlled manner was disastrous
for human progress, basically, and
is the source of just untold trillions
of dollars of malinvestment, and, you
know, if we didn't have the that system
in place, that humanity would be way
more advanced than it is. I was really
into that, and I was thinking that for
years before I got into Bitcoin. And so
that was where it first started. I was
like, "This is like the answer." That
this is, you know,
the clear next step for
human economy
to to go past, you know, this era, this
post-war like central bank-controlled
fiat era. For when I first discovered
Bitcoin, I was working at a think tank
in DC that was like an economic policy
think tank that was very to like sound
money ideas and and and very kind of not
sympathetic to
uh central banking-controlled
economies and things like that. Um so
that was like the primary thing is I
just thought it was very powerful just
for humanity and the you know, I say
like I was was in it for the tech, but
the cool thing about Bitcoin is it's
like the tech and the financial aspect
and the social aspects all uh
so clear-cut for me as I wish it would
have been. I mean, it was still I think
I was a little bit ahead of the curve,
but
that definitely wasn't like my initial
drive. It wasn't like, "Oh, I need to
get so into this because I'm going to
get so rich." It was like, "I need to
get into this because it's so powerful."
or whatever.
>> Well, if you don't really like big
institutions, Wall Street, and all that,
what do you think about them joining
>> that I don't like big big institutions.
It's like that perversion of the price
of money from central banking.
What is now basically explicit bailout
guarantees for the largest financial
institutions, and so obviously that
in inflates to a degree we won't be able
to quantify, but is a massive degree. It
inflates the size of what the firm would
otherwise be, because as firms grow,
they get less agile and less
uh you know,
less able to to to shift if as the
economy changes as and as things change.
Let's say we don't have fiat, and it's
all on Bitcoin standard. Yeah. What the
what would the world be like? There like
Is there a stock market?
>> Oh, there'd be it it it it would be a a
rocket ship into our You're discussing
our inevitable, incredible future. No,
of course there's a stock market. Of
course there's the the markets would be
more dynamic than ever before. All
markets.
Uh
>> But the price what Well, if it's Bitcoin
standard, then
how do you It's hard for me to picture.
>> it in Bitcoin. But what I'm really
saying is, okay, let's say this whole
market, there are only two companies,
you and me.
So every
dollar or every Bitcoin that I gain is
from you. So So it's like a zero
zero-sum game.
Uh well, the that's the unit of measure.
The amount of um
value that humanity can create in the
aggregate is is infinite, and it's not
defined by the denominator,
you know, so so in that way it's like
it's not really zero-sum. Each Bitcoin
is You know, they like the thing was
like infinity divided by 21 million,
that each Bitcoin can represent an
infinite amount of economic activity.
Does that make sense? It does make
sense.
But you're still talking about dollar,
right? Like a hundred dollars, this
Yeah, but if I gave you one Bitcoin as
well, it's the same it's the same
uh analogy.
Okay, I have a hard time understanding
>> Like I could hold all my Bitcoin that I
hold. I mean, obviously I'd like to save
Bitcoin. I like to save it.
>> Bitcoin in the world, and only Well, we
can say there's 21 million. Let's say
there's 21 million Bitcoin in the world.
Just just for me to calculate easier,
like yeah, yeah. So 10 Bitcoin, and
there are only a few companies in the
world. Now,
>> Okay. you said there will still be a
stock market, Yeah. which means if my
stock goes up
one Bitcoin, somebody else's stock has
to go down one Bitcoin, or like the Uh
collectively, I don't know, goes up
20x in two years, you won't see anything
like that anymore.
>> If there's only 10 Bitcoin,
think about it something easier. Like
there's 10 Bitcoin,
but you need to eat, so you're going to
spend a few satoshis to go buy a
sandwich. You're not going to say, "No,
I'll I'll I'll I'll starve today, and
I'll starve tomorrow, and I'm not going
to eat ever again because I want to get
maximum amount of Bitcoin." If you want
to get the maximum amount of Bitcoin,
you probably are going to need to spend
a few satoshis on some groceries,
because otherwise you're going to be
dead. And if you're dead, you can't get
Bitcoin.
>> what I'm trying to say is it's harder to
get rich. No, no, no, it's it's much
easier to get rich. Well, yeah, because
there's so much malinvestment. The
market signal that the price signal is
going to be so much healthier. It's
going to be
>> That is true.
>> So it's going You're going to have a
much more efficient market when you have
a Bitcoin standard. And so of course
there's going to be businesses that
outperform Bitcoin. If you have a if you
have a Bitcoinized economy, Bitcoin is
going to be a relatively stable asset.
It'll probably be one of the most stable
assets because it's like the denominator
for all the activity in the economy.
>> In this world that you're describing, do
we still have
>> inevitable, incredible future. It's
going to happen. Uh we probably still
have fiat because the governments are
going to be printing it to try to have
their last vestige of like of like
control and relevance, but the fiat's
essentially going to be like
food stamp money.
>> Right. Right.
>> It's going to be it's going to be like,
you know, as it dies off it's going to
be used to like placate those who don't
have Bitcoin basically. How much time do
we have until then?
I don't know.
Say at least 25 years it's got to be. 25
years?
I don't know. I mean it's hard to say
because you could have catalyst events.
Like for example?
>> Like the bond market failing. So you
have like
massive debt burden.
And like governments the world over
incredible amounts of debt that are I
believe unprecedented in in the history
of humanity and no one's
even pretending like they're doing
anything to stop it.
>> It's a you can't stop it.
What what can you realistically do to
stop it? It's designed
>> or like the governments what could they
do?
>> Well, they could like stop spending.
But they won't. No, they won't exactly.
So what what could they do? They could
lower spending.
>> Mhm.
>> They could increase revenues which is
like increase taxes or they can monetize
it. Clearly they're going to monetize
it. But if they do that they won't get
elected. If they do that they won't get
elected.
No, they won't get elected. If you raise
taxes you won't get elected. If you
reduce spending you won't get elected.
If you monetize it it's a much more
obscured opaque delayed taxation scheme.
Push your
country into hyperinflation isn't great
for your electoral chances but it's
better than the other two options. So
they're going to monetize the debt and
long story short what's I mean
We're like maybe we're ways away. I
don't know how much more load it can
take at least in the US which is
fiscally relevant country on earth
probably at least in the west. But it
probably I mean it's like the largest
government on earth and the debt burden
you know whatever you have we're at 38
trillion dollars. Maybe it can go to 138
trillion. Maybe that takes 20 years but
at some point
there will the bond market will break.
The bonds will not be worth purchasing.
But probably the bond market will break
and there'll be like a rush a rush to
Bitcoin and then governments all over
the world will try to like clamp down on
Bitcoin and they'll try to close the on
ramps and off ramps or they'll do
there's a whole bunch of things they
could do. They could like be they could
proactively like embrace Bitcoin and
start to like get exposure to Bitcoin to
try to shore up their
currencies. Some will probably do that
um and they'll benefit from it but
probably a lot of governments will
go to try to like slam the gates on the
exits and initiate like Bitcoin centric
capital controls. They won't benefit
from that in the long term and it but
individuals might really suffer. Pretty
much exactly what
the US did with private gold holdings in
um whenever that was 37 or whatever.
The debt problem that you were talking
about are they trying to solve it with
stablecoin? In a way yeah. I guess the
stablecoin is seen as like maybe the
solution for reduced foreign interest in
in US debt. I think it's actually
going to work at least for quite some
time. It buys a lot of time but it's
also introducing like a poison pill from
that perspective because these rails are
obviously like overlap with Bitcoin. It
gets people used to
using digital currencies help accelerate
Bitcoinization is going to act like a
stepping stone towards like
Bitcoinization at the individual level.
Let's say we swap the government
and you're now the president of
this country and you can Of Hong Kong?
Whatever country right?
>> Cool yeah.
>> Yeah and
>> President of Hong Kong that sounds cool.
>> And now you can bring on all the
Bitcoiners and you can reset the
financial rules of a country. What would
you do? It's a horrible job. It would be
horrible.
I would slash spending slash the size of
the government
slash it.
>> Yeah it maybe it wouldn't work. I don't
know. I don't know what exactly what
Dodge did or what they were trying to do
or whatever but
it's like an impossible thing. I mean
that's literally what deficit spending
is when you're when you're talking about
deficit spending at the nation state
level it's taking
from
the grandkids and great grandchildren to
spend on yourself. You're like literally
taking from quality of life from future
generations to to subsidize your quality
of life. It's it's
it's evil. It's horrible.
>> think you could do that forever then
it's not evil anymore because they can
do that forever.
>> do it forever for their lifespans like
you know many people who initiated this
they're they're not going to be alive
when the
when the bill comes due and the
some sort of
systematic reset will will will need to
occur. It's inevitable because
there's no plan to
to address the debt. There's no plan to
pay it off. You're the president you can
do whatever you want.
So uh that's not really the way it
works. [laughter]
Yeah and print yeah. Just print print
print. Just print the money and buy
Bitcoin.
>> Maybe that That's the only way to do it.
You print the money and buy Bitcoin
you'll be the first to do it. You can't
be the last to like you can't can't
wait.
You're the you're the 57th country to do
it you're screwed. If you're the
especially if you're the size of the US
you have the reserve currency of the
world you know you might as well take
advantage start printing get some
Bitcoin.
Well, that's what all the treasury
companies are doing.
Well, they can't print money like the
Federal Reserve can.
>> They can borrow cheaply and they can
borrow more cheaply than individuals
even like you know high net worth
individuals. So that's like uh
that's the kind of the hack here you
know that's the inherent advantage if
you want to acquire as much uh
uh Bitcoin as possible um you know front
load it then that's the way you can do
it. One way one way you can do it and so
that's why we're seeing this takeoff and
there's going to be a bunch of other
ways that people
haven't thought of or haven't done yet
and there's going to be like conduits
into every
aspect of the market. There's going to
be um
waves like going into
into fixed income and even into
municipal debt. Uh
um all sorts of stuff like that. It's
going to be interesting. There's going
to be
the Bitcoinization of of
all the capital in the world is is like
a tall order. So there's going to be a
lot of
paths and conduits for the capital to
flow into Bitcoin.
Right now it's all the companies but in
the future
maybe
maybe countries will actually print to
buy Bitcoin.
>> Yeah yeah.
I think that's certain. I mean it's
certain they're going to do it
somebody's going to do it
but uh
uh
you know when that starts in earnest
we'll see. It's going to be interesting.
But it's definitely going to happen for
sure. Thoughts on Ethereum treasury
company?
Why not? Like let's just turn all the
stock markets into crypto exchanges and
yolo.
I mean like
it's better
than most of the like zombies and trash
listed on the stock markets. Are you a
Bitcoin only person? Yeah. You are?
>> Pretty much yeah. Mhm.
So you think all coins like all the
other DATs they might work?
Well, it's on a I mean depends on what
scale you're talking about. I don't know
that in that regard I'm probably not
going to be an investor in
in in many
uh altcoin DATs but it is interesting to
turn all these all the capital markets
into like
Bitcoin exchanges and crypto exchanges
so let's let's let's see it.
It seems like you are having fun in this
whole thing. Like people look at it as
really serious stuff but you you just
have this yeah it's fun that type of
vibe. It's fun yeah. It's fun to do
things.
>> let's try this let's try that you know.
Yeah I mean I don't know.
Yeah.
I guess I'm you know
lucky enough to be in this position
and it's a very interesting industry and
then like you know
all the smartest people I meet they're
in this industry. Mhm. And I meet other
people and they're not in the industry
they're not as smart.
>> [laughter]
>> So it's probably a good sign you know.
What would happen in 10 years? In 10
years we sit here again we're talking
what's happening now.
Uh yeah. All the government debt levels
will be way way way higher.
Uh Bitcoin will be way higher.
Uh the the mind share for Bitcoin
globally will be much higher as well.
It's like Bitcoin will be will be like
standard in their brain. It's normal.
It's not like some brand new space age
technology like it is for
the geriatrics who
hold the vast majority of the wealth on
earth. I mean the vast vast majority of
the wealth on earth is held by extremely
elderly people and so 10 years from now
a lot of those people will have passed
away and the money that wealth will be
held by younger people and that just is
a process that will continue for some
time most likely
as the old people will die and then
hopefully more
babies will be born and they'll grow up
and
eventually Bitcoin's going to be like
super normal
uh
technology that has like existed their
entire lives. You know it's like a a
teenager today doesn't find an iPad to
be a like insanely
uh
novel thing or something that they don't
understand. It's like very normal to
them. They understand it very well. So,
no Bitcoin conferences anymore cuz it's
so normal.
>> Well, there's probably a lot of Bitcoin
conferences because there's a lot of
conferences for all sorts of stuff
that's been around forever, you know?
There's like train conferences.
The trains have been around a long time.
That is true. And there's like, you
know, car conferences. Mhm. Auto shows.
Yeah.
>> But the the
autos have been around a while.
They're selling the parts and they're
selling the cars. But if Bitcoin is
normalized,
are people There'll be all sorts of
stuff to sell. You can sell like all
sorts of financial services and custody
services and uh
mining equipment or and all sort of
probably stuff I haven't really thought
of, but
it'll be a mass It's going to be huge.
Okay. You've been around
>> You've been around for a very long time
and there are still people watching this
show. Maybe they are still hesitant.
I don't know. Advice.
If they're hesitant to to buy Bitcoin or
to hold Bitcoin?
>> they could still be hesitant like
they they hear about it, but it's still
something
>> are you going to hold? It's the only
thing that's It's like the only free
market left.
I mean, everything else is fake and
trash.
What are you going to like They print
infinite
money. Dollars and everything every not
just dollars, all the all the fiat
currencies. Wherever you are, whatever
currency that your government is like
forcing you to trade in, it's trash.
They just print infinite.
There's no limit. They can print forever
and they will print forever.
Uh
and Bitcoin is like it's scarce
to an artificial degree. It's scarce
beyond like the physical world. There's
Everything else that's ever existed
is um
keeps We keep getting more and more of
it, right? It's Imagine like gold we we
Big gold's been like a monetary asset
that's highly highly sought after for
thousands of years now. And then every
year there's still 1 or 2% more gold
pulled out and increased The supply is
increased. And the supply will like keep
increasing. There's like gold in every
body of water. There's gold
in mountains still. There's gold in
outer space. Massive amounts of gold.
There's like infinite gold. The only
thing there's not
infinite of
is Bitcoin. It's the It's like it's a
It's artificial level of scarcity. It's
like an It's a synthetic level of
scarcity that has never existed in the
physical realm in the real world. It's
something like completely novel in that
way. Are we still early?
I Yeah, probably yeah. Definitely. I
mean, I don't know there's many There's
levels of early, Yeah.
>> but it's still very If If If Bitcoin's
going to be the the you know, reference
unit for economic activity for the next
hundreds of years at least, then yeah,
we're very early.
In that case, I need your
price prediction.
Price prediction? For when?
>> For
Well, end of the year is a little too
short. Let's do end of the year, 5
years, 10 years, 20 years.
Uh end of the year is
I mean, I guess the most likely would be
just the price that it is today.
>> Mhm.
At the end of the year cuz it's like
almost the end of the year. So, I don't
know what is the price of Bitcoin today
like 110,000.
Uh
5 years?
Who knows?
5 years, maybe like a
350 350,000. What is it 10 years?
Maybe like 1.2 million 10 years from
now. It's a long time, 10 years.
Especially for something like this.
And 20 years?
I don't know.
1.4 million.
Okay, advice for people. Do you think
people should actually because we're
still early and because it's going to go
up in value, what should I do now? Like
should I do whatever it takes to buy as
many as I can? Yeah. Definitely.
Like get a job and buy Bitcoin. Get two
jobs.
>> Get two jobs if you need two jobs, yeah.
I mean, like do whatever you can because
the clock is ticking and clearly like
uh more and more money interests
are becoming aware. We're clearly on the
right trajectory
that more and more people and more and
more capital is going to want to get
into Bitcoin. And so, one actually
advantage that individuals have is the
potential to move and move quickly. When
you have these large institutions, they
have a lot of money, but they have, you
know, all these bureaucrats that need to
feel significant and have all these
meetings with each other to talk about,
you know, our risk
matrix and
If you're an individual, you don't have
that. Like, you know, maybe you have
someone you need to like bounce it off
of that you live with. I don't know.
Whatever, but you like you have
a lot more flexibility. So,
go and throw whatever spare change you
can
while you can
because it's been a great idea always
like so far.
Everyone who's done that has benefited
massively. But if you're watching this
and you have like a semblance of
of like duty to your future self and
your, you know, future friends and
family um and you're not like completely
financially illiterate and completely
irresponsible, then buy as much Bitcoin
as you can like today and save money.
The money is If the money is Bitcoin,
then you have some alpha because a lot
of the money that's being saved out
there in the world, they don't know that
yet. So, you have a little edge. So, go
and get as much Bitcoin as quickly as
possible as you can and it I think will
be a good idea.
You've seen Bitcoin at a really really
cheap price. Are you still buying now?
Yeah. What do I I've been every every
cent of income that I've had since
whenever I got into it when I was
telling you back in the day, every cent
I I put in the Bitcoin. Always from that
point until now.
>> Well, what else are you going to do with
it?
I don't know. Enjoy life. Everything
else is garbage. Well, you enjoy life.
Yeah, enjoy life, but what do you mean?
Like you spend You want to I should go
spend recklessly? That's the key?
I mean, enjoy life. What does that mean?
>> As in like, okay, should I not go on
this trip? You should save money. What
are you talking about? I don't know. You
just enjoy Enjoy your life. Yeah, but
you need to save money. So, if you're
going to save money, then save Bitcoin.
Mhm. I see.
>> Bitcoin is like the money now. Most
people don't realize. So, save Bitcoin.
If you want to go spend frivolously, you
can do that, but it's going to like not
be great in the future.
You can go look at like some pair Oh, I
bought this like fancy thing, fancy pair
of shoes. You think that 12 years from
now you're going to like look at the
shoes and be like, "Wow, they gave me so
much pleasure. [laughter] I'm so glad I
spent a thousand dollars on some shoes.
Wow, that was such a great idea." You're
going to be like, "No, I could have
spent a thousand dollars. I could have
had one Bitcoin. Now it's worth so much.
Look how much."
That's probably what you'll be doing.
Probably what you'll be thinking. Okay,
let's say Let's say you really want a
car right now.
And
if you don't buy it now when you're 90
with all the Bitcoins in the world, now
you're like, "I'm too old to even drive
my dream car.
But I could have." I don't know. If you
like Are you like so into the cars, then
buy a car.
>> I guess it's like the balance, right?
Whatever However you want to take it.
>> where you can afford a car, you'll know
it. Yeah, yeah, yeah. Most people can't
shouldn't be buying some stupid car.
Most people should not be doing that.
They should be saving money. The only
way you're going to save money and get
out ahead I mean, not the only way, but
the best way on a risk-adjusted basis
almost certainly is to buy Bitcoin. I
mean, Bitcoin is extremely liquid. It's
getting more liquid every day.
It's just like most likely it's a better
idea for the vast majority of people
than to buy a depreciating asset that I
mean, like a car
it
gets you around, so there's a
utilitarian aspect. And then you can
have like, "Okay, this is my dream car."
So, I guess it's like, you know, it's
fun or whatever. But financially, it's a
disaster. It's a depreciating asset that
just consumes, consumes, and consumes
and then gets scrapped or like sold, you
know, for big loss or whatever. So, it's
like, "Okay, we can have you can buy the
car, I guess." What is the meaning of
your life?
What's the meaning of my life?
>> Mhm. What's the ultimate goal?
Um to have
uh like a happy
healthy
uh family. Mhm. I think.
Happy, healthy family, but it has
nothing to do with Bitcoin now.
Well, that's Well, Bitcoin lends to
that. Of course. I mean, Bitcoin
>> [snorts]
>> makes it much easier to have a happy,
healthy family. Mhm. To be like
financially secure and independent and
not have to
uh
worry about the um
potential
monetary collapse of the fiat currency
regimes. Makes it much easier to
have a happy, healthy life.
Or to probably do anything
Whatever your goal is, even if it's like
the most crazy hedonistic all the way to
the most noble, selfless, any Whatever
your goal is, it makes it easier. I'm
almost certain.
Thank you so much for being here today.
I loved it. Thank you so much.
>> pleasure.